Register of the Ekaterina Nikolaevna Vagner Papers, 1876-1936
Hoover Institution Archives
Ekaterina Nikolaevna Vagner Papers,
1876-1936
37001
Vagner, Ekaterina Nikolaevna.
2 manuscript boxes 0.8 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Correspondence, writings, diaries, and printed matter, relating to revolutionary movements and events in Russia. Includes a study by N. N. Dzvonkevich (father of E. N. Vagner), entitled Reminiscences, relating to the Strelnikovskii trial in Odessa; and letters from Ekaterina Breshko-Breshkovskaia
Administrative Information
Access
Collection open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1937.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Access Points
Partiia sotsialistov-revoliutsionerov.; Revolutionaries--Russia.; Russia.; Soviet Union.; Soviet Union--History--Revolution, 1917-1921.
Container List
- Two letters (1910, 1938), of E. K. Breshkovskaiia to E. N. Dzvonkevich-Wagner (Box 1., Folder 1)
- Manuscript of an article "Nihilism and Socialism" by N. N. Dzvonkevich, written while in exile, 1885 (Folder 2)
- Notes of N. N. Dzvonkevich concerning the Kadainskii mines, where he worked during his exile in Siberia (Folder 3)
- Notes of N. N. Dzvonkevich concerning nihilism in Kiev. Written while in exile, 1885-1886 (Folder 4)
- Biographical notes on N. N. Dzvonkevich (Folder 5)
- Poetry, in Ukrainian, written by N. N. Dzvonkevich, 1884-1889, while in exile (Folder 6)
- Two copies of letters from inmates of a Moscow prison, 1920 (Folder 7)
- Four letters to E. N. Dzvonkevich-Wagner from E. E. Lazarev (Folder 8)
- One letter from the Social Revolutionary Party to the editors of the Jitsusyo-no-Nihon, Tokyo (Folder 9)
- One letter from Nina A. Struve to M. I. Pisarev, 1902 (Folder 10)
- Congratulatory letter from Bolsheviks, in exile on Capri, to P. A. Kropotkin on his 70th birthday (Folder 11)
- Postcards concerning the Russian Civil War (Folder 12)
- Three letters to E. N. Dzvonkevich-Wagner from V. M. Chernov, leader of the Social Revolutionary Party (Folder 13)
- One letter from Herman Bernstein to the publishers of "Volia Rossii," 1921 (Folder 14)
- Twenty-six letters from C. M. Oberutchev to E. N. Dzvonkevich-Wagner (Folder 15)
- Three letters from Polivanov to M. I. Pisarev, 1903 (Folder 16)
- Correspondence file of A. Khristoforov (Folder 17)
- Notes of N. N. Dzvonkevich-Wagner during the period of his departure for Serbia, 1876 (Folder 18)
- Diary of N. N. Dzvonkevich, in exile, 1884-1891 (Folder 19)
- Memoirs on the Strelnikovskii Trial in Odessa, written by E. N. Dzvonkevich-Wagner (Folder 20)
- Twelve letters of E. K. Breshkovskaia, 1910-1916 (Folder 21)
- 253 letters to E. N. Dzvonkevich-Wagner from N. N. Dzvonkevich, 1881-1908 (Box 2., Folder 1)
- Miscellaneous correspondence, manuscripts, typescripts, notes and other printed materials (Folder 2)